SAMUEL JACOBO **GARAVITO SEGURA**

APPLYCATION

PYTHON/RPA Developer

PERSONAL INFO

Name: Samuel Jacobo Garavito Segura.

I.D. 1192798537.

Date of Birth: 06/01/2001.

Place of Birth: Bogotá D.C. Colombia.

Marital Status: Single.

Address: 69N avenue # 63C - 33

Phone: +57 3208631814. **E-Mail:** sgaravito@unal.edu.co.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-

jacobo-garavito-segura-mathpy/

GitHub: https://github.com/SgaravitoWp

PROFILE

Mathematics student with operational experience working as a Python/RPA developer and debugger in charge of finding solutions for data extraction and manipulation. Front-end Web experience with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Bootstrap. Able to create responsive and attractive websites. Data with IPython/Jupyter Science experience Notebooks. Able to implement, document and interpret regression models results for decision making. Proficiency in Python (2 years) with frameworks using object-oriented different programming together with control versioning tools such as Git and Github. Good statistical/ mathematical background and experience working with hypothesis testing, goodness of fit and regression models.

LANGUAGES

Spanish English

Native Speaker Fluent (C1 level)

WORK EXPERIENCE

From MAR/2022 to present (Bogotá D.C. - Colombia)

Pidgin Contact Solutions

Python Developer

Tasks: In charge of task automation by means of RPA's for data extraction and manipulation with Python. Besides, responsible of debugging tasks of form and efficiency.

Main packages: Selenium WebDriver and

Pandas.

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/company/pidgincontactsolutions/mycompany/

From AUG/2021 to present (Bogotá D.C. - Colombia)

FreeLancer

Tasks: In charge of providing solutions for the projects entrusted. For example: Web design, statistical reports, API design, etc.

Main packages: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Django, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

2018 to present **Degree: Mathematician aspirant**

Bogotá D.C.

National University of

Colombia Colombia

2017

Degree: Academic Bachelor Liceo of Cervantes Augustinian

Priests

Bogotá D.C. Colombia

CERTIFICATES

2022

Python Specialization

Bogotá D.C. Colombia Michigan University (United States)

Courses

- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) (Done)
- 2. Python Data Structures (Done)
- 3. Using Python to Access Web Data (Done)
- 4. Using Databases with Python (Done)
- Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python (In progress)

2022

Introduction to control versioning with Git and GitHub

Bogotá D.C. Colombia

Andes University (Colombia)

2021

Software Development Diploma

Bogotá D.C. Colombia North University (Colombia)

2021 Bogotá D.C.

Colombia

Programing Fundamentals Diploma

North University (Colombia)

2021

Basic Programming DiplomaNorth University (Colombia)

Bogotá D.C. Colombia

SKILLS

Python

NumPy Pandas Matplotlib Scipy Flask Selenium

Web development

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript Bootstrap

Other

C++ LaTeX

PROJECTS

From FEB/2022 to present

About me

Github repository with all my completed and in progress projects.

- Percolation and Critical Probability Project: In this project, together with my partners Jose Beleno and Luis Rojas, we studied the percolation process through a computational simulation.
- Evaluation of Random Number Generation Methods Project. (In progress)
- Bayesian Perspective Project. (In progress)

GitHub Repo:

https://github.com/SgaravitoWp/About_Me.git

JUN/2022

OlimAPI

Here you can find an API designed for managing the execution of an RPA that queries company information on the portal https://www.einforma.co/buscador-empresas-empresarios.

GitHub Repo:

https://github.com/SgaravitoWp/OlimpiaIT.git